# Farah Yeazneen

Brooklyn, NY | 347-369-7748 | farahctg10@gmail.com | www.linkedin.com/in/yeazneen

## **SUMMARY**

Highly motivated and solution-driven Front-End Developer with experience in HTML, CSS, JavaScript and React.JS. Junior Data analyst with professional experience in SQL, Tableau, Python, and data visualization. Currently, pursuing BS in Computer Science. Proven ability to tackle difficult projects and collaborate with team. Possess in-depth knowledge of Object-Oriented Programming.

### **SKILLS**

JavaScript,	React.js,	SQL,	Tableau,	Salesforce,	GitHub,
HTML,	Node.js,	MySQL,	Python,	MS Office,	Git,
CSS,	REST API,	MongoDB,	Excel,	Agile,	JIRA,
Bootstrap	Postman	XML	JSON	JSX	C++
MS Office	Google Workspace				

### **EDUCATION**

The City College of New York, New York, NY

**Bachelor in Science**: Computer Science **Graduation Date:** December 2023

**Borough of Manhattan Community** College, New York, NY

Associate in Science: Computer Science Graduation Date: December 2020

#### TECHNICAL EXPERIENCE

#### **General Assembly**

December 2021 - June 2022

Software Engineering Immersive, Bootcamp

- Collaborated with a team of 3 UX Designers and 8 fellow Software Engineering students to build a full-stack website
- Completed over 20+ assignments on HTML, CSS, JavaScript, Node.js, React.js, MERN Stack and Python
- Spent 420+ hours learning software engineering skills from industry expert instructors

#### **TECHNICAL PROJECTS**

- *To-Do App:* Created a To-Do app with **HTML**, **CSS**, **Bootstrap** and **JavaScrip**t to implement **CURD** operation
- *OMDB Movie API*: Built an app with **React.js**, **CSS** and **OMDB API** to search, fetch and display movie data from OMDB

- Roaming Spoon: Created a full-stack web app with team to find and review food trucks using React.js, Node.js, MongoDB, CSS, JavaScript, HTML
- YouTube Data API: Built an app with Python to scrape YouTube data using YouTube Data API.
  Extracted and loaded data into Python Pandas Data Frame, visualized data with Python Seaborn library

### **PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE**

## **Junior Data Analyst**

January 2022 – Present

NYC Department of Buildings, Manhattan, NY

- Ensure 100% accuracy of data collection and reporting by validating data integrity
- Collect and analyze data related to COVID positive test cases from 1772 DOE schools situated at DOB premises
- Update and manage data on MySQL server by using SQL
- Collaborate with DOE, DOB, DOHMH to identify, assess, and solve business problems
- Create reports for school principals by using advanced Excel
- Create and manage dashboards on Tableau to visualize COVID positive cases by borough, school district and school

## **Medical Receptionist**

July 2021 – January 2022

Multi-Specialty Medical Office, Brooklyn, NY

- Processed and verified new patient's information within 7-8 minutes
- Performed a variety of administrative tasks in a high-volume medical practice
- Collected co-payments, insurance information and other methods of payments
- Organized and updated files for 3K+ patients according to HIPAA guidelines with 100% accuracy, contributed to reducing error in data entry
- Scheduled 30+ appointments per day according to patients' preference and physician's availability

# **Application Support Specialist**

May 2021 – July 2021

Fingercheck, Brooklyn, NY

- Configured cloud-based HR software to meet clients' needs, troubleshot technical problems
- Documented calls and chats with clients using Salesforce software
- Identified and escalated issues that can't be resolved via level 1 support
- Provided technical and software support to over 20 clients daily via phone call, email and live chat via Intercom

#### **Administrative Assistant**

September 2016 – May 2021

YS Farm Country Corporation, Brooklyn, NY

- Answered, transferred phone calls and emails in a prompt manner
- Managed and processed day-to-day payments to vendors using Accounting Edge
- Helped in processing weekly payroll for 70+ employees
- Prepared daily sales report for 3 stores on Excel
- Trained 3 employees by preparing them for their roles
- Analyzed monthly bank reconciliation reports and bank's records for irregularities